
========================

= TEAM =

ABBYY (www.abbyy.com), Konstantin Zuyev, Vladimir Lapshin

= DESCRIPTION OF RUN =

Syntactic Analysis + Tree Matching + Similiarity Score by Estimation of Matching

= TOOLS USED =

* Lemmatizer
* Multiword expressions recognition
* Syntax parser
* Semantic Role Labeling
* Word Sense Disambiguation
* Lexical Substitution
* Knowledge-based similarity
* Correference

= RESOURCES USED =

* Multilingual corpora
* Other dictionaries - proprietary Semantic Hierarchy 

= METHOD TO COMBINE TOOLS AND RESOURCES =


ABBYY's Compreno Parser is used to build semantic trees of the sentences. Semantic tree is a directional acyclic graph, with vertices that are signed with elements of ABBYY's Semantic Hierarchy. Semantic tree is the representaion of semantic structure (WSD, Semantic Role Labeling, Correference) of the parsed sentence. To reduce the ambiguity in parsing the Parser was ran in parallel mode, i.e. parsing both sentences simultaniously to produce coordinated structures if possible.
Tree matching from Bilingual Tree Matching algorithm was adapted to process pairs of sentences of the single language. The sentences trees' nodes are mapped to produce a partial set of node pairs (some trees nodes do not have a pair). 
TheSimiliarity Score algorithm goes through the mapped set of nodes and calculate nodes distance in terms of [0;1] interval values. Then the weights of all nodes are summed to produce the final distance. The algorithm has several parameters (e.g. the nodes' notions are equal, non vocabulary text are exactly equal or case insensitive equal, one node is parent of another one in the Semantic Hierarchy and etc.). The parameter valuse are calculated based on the training data STS.input.MSRpar.txt and STS.input.MSRvid.txt by using optimization procedure. The Differential Evolution optimization algorithm was used.


= COMMENTS =

Some improvements could be done:
1. Use monolingual paraphrases.
2. Bilingual tree matching can be tuned to the task of monolingual matching.
3. Tree node similiarity measure uses weights obtained for translation task. These weights should be retrained for semantic similiarity task.
	

